thesocialelement.agency 2019-05-14

# Privacy Policy - The Social Element

The Social Element Limited is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This privacy policy (together with our [Website Terms and Conditions found here](https://thesocialelement.agency/terms-and-conditions/) and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. This privacy policy will also inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

Please read this privacy policy carefully to understand our approach to your personal data. Our aim is always to give you appropriate notice of any data we will collect about you and how it will be used. We will only process your data if we assess it is fair and lawful to do so.

### 1\. Important information and who we are

 **Purpose of this privacy policy**

This privacy policy aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you, for example, sign up to our newsletter, complete surveys or online forms, or purchase our services.

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

 **Controller**

The Social Element Limited is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “The Social Element”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy policy).

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including any requests to exercise _your legal rights_ , please contact the DPO using the details set out below.

 **Contact details**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our privacy practices, please contact our DPO in the following ways:

Full name of legal entity: Treena Hales – Chief Operating Officer

Email address: __[dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency](mailto:dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency)__

Postal address: 2 Riding House Street, London, W1W 7FA, UK

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

 **Changes to the privacy policy and your duty to inform us of changes**

We keep our privacy policy under regular review. This version was last updated on March 14, 2019. Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

 **Third-party links**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

### 2\. The data we collect about you

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  *  **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.
  *  **Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  *  **Financial Data** includes bank account and payment card details.
  *  **Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
  *  **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  *  **Profile Data** includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  *  **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
  *  **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data could be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data will **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

 **If you fail to provide personal data**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

### 3\. How is your personal data collected?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

 **Direct interactions** **.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * apply for our services;
  * subscribe to our service or publications;
  * request marketing to be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * give us feedback or contact us.

 **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see [The Social Element Cookie Policy](https://thesocialelement.agency/cookie-policy/) for further details.

 **Third parties.** We will receive personal data about you from various third parties which may include, as set out below:

  * analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU (Technical Data, Usage Data); and
  * marketing and sales networks such as Mailchimp, LinkedIn and Salesforce based outside the EU (Identity Data, Contact Data).

### 4\. How we use your personal data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal obligation.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data although we will get your consent before sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

 **Purposes for which we will use your personal data**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. Please see the end of the table below for glossary of the terms used relating to lawful basis for processing.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

 **Marketing**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:

 ** _Promotional offers from us_**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased services from us and you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

We may send the following commercial communications by email to a targeted selection of individuals from our marketing database: invitations to industry events we are hosting or attending; newsletters; industry updates; updates about our agency and the services we offer; other information that we reasonably think may be of interested to our contacts.

 ** _Marketing database_**

Our marketing database includes data of: staff members of our clients; individuals who have requested us to send marketing information by completing a form on our website, sending us an email or via a phone call; individuals we have met at events or via online public forums or social media who have asked us to send marketing information.

 ** _Third-party marketing_**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes.

 ** _Customer Relationship Management_**

As with many agencies and other businesses we use a Customer Relationship Management database (“CRM”) to manage and assess our contact with people who are interested in our services. Our CRM will include people to whom we already deliver services and people we believe we may deliver services to in the future. The personal data on the CRM will include information publicly available such as job title and name of company. It may also include information added by our team members based on their interactions with you. If you wish to be excluded from our CRM please contact  _ _[dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency](mailto:dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency)__ _._

 ** _Opting out_**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by replying directly to our marketing messages sent to you requesting to be unsubscribed, or by contacting us at any time. Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a service purchase, service experience or other transactions.

 **Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see <https://thesocialelement.agency/cookie-policy/>

**Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### 5\. Disclosures of your personal data

We may share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.

 **External third parties:**

  * Service providers based internationally who provide marketing and IT and system administration services.
  * Amazon Web Services, Salesforce, Tableau, Google.

 **Other third parties:** other third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy policy.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### 6\. International transfers

Many of our external third parties are based outside the EEA so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Where we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

### 7\. Data security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### 8\. Data retention

 **How long will you use my personal data for?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see _your legal rights_ below for further information.

In some circumstances we will anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

### 9\. Your legal rights

Under certain circumstances, you have the following rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data:

 **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

 **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

 **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

 **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

 **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:

  * If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy.
  * Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it.
  * Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.
  * You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

 **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

 **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact [_dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency_](mailto:dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency).

 **No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

 **What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

 **Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### 10\. Online Job Applications

If you submit an enquiry about one of our job vacancies online, we will store and use the information you provide (which may include a CV) for the purposes of assessing your suitability for the role.  
If you are offered a role you will be provided with our staff privacy policy which will give your more information about how we process and safeguard your personal data.  
If you are not offered a role we will retain your data for 12 months in case a new opportunity arises or there are any queries or concerns about our recruitment process.  
After this time we will either delete your data, or, if we think there may be a role suitable for you in the future we will contact you to ask if you would like us to continue to keep your information for that purpose. If we do not hear from you or you decline, we will delete your information. We will continue this process every 12 months.

If at any time you wish us to not consider you for a future role and/or would like us to delete your information, please contact  _ _[dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency](mailto:dataprotection@thesocialelement.agency)__.
